nationalparkstraveler.com 2019-04-18

# Privacy Policy | National Parks Traveler

NATIONAL PARKS TRAVELER AND NATIONAL PARKS TRAVELER WEBSITE

Last updated – Ma 14, 2017

This Privacy Policy applies to information collected at [www.nationalparkstraveler.org](https://www.nationalparkstraveler.org/), and online services owned or operated by National Parks Traveler (Site).

By accessing and continuing to use the Site you acknowledge that you have read and that you agree to the practices described in this Privacy Policy and the Site may use the information provided in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

 **1\. Information Collected**

a.  **Personally-Identifiable Information (“Personal Information”)**

National Parks Traveler and the Site and their service providers only collect Personal Information that you voluntarily submit, for example by signing up for the National Parks Traveler newsletter or registering as a User to post comments in the User Interactive Areas, or if you email or mail us directly. Depending on the service you choose or the form of the submission, the Personal Information collected may include your name, email address, address, phone number, website name, and website URL, organizational affiliation and/or similar information.

b.  **Information That May be Collected Automatically**

In addition to information you provide to us, the Site and our service providers may use standard technologies to automatically collect certain information. For example, we may collect IP address, social media ID, browser type, mobile device type, content visited while on the Site, address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version. Collecting browser activities or IP addresses, along with the time of the visit and the page(s) that were visited, are common practices, and are often performed automatically by many websites, applications and other services for such purposes as calculating usage levels, helping diagnose server problems, and administering the Site.

We may use third-party web and mobile app analytics and optimization services to improve the Site and enhance the visitor experience by, for example, recording mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity as well as text you type in the Site.

We may use “Cookies” and similar technology, to obtain information about your visits to the Sites or your responses to our e-mails or other electronic communications – both individually and in an aggregated form.  A cookie is a short text file that may be stored on your hard drive when you visit a website.

We may use the following types of cookies on the Site:

  * Display and preference settings cookies that remember the size of text or other preferences.
  * Transient (also called “session ID”) cookies to provide continuity from page to page. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser.
  * Cookies that track whether a social networking option has been used to forward material from our Site (so that we know which social networking tools are in use).
  * We also may log your domain and IP address automatically when you visit the Site. This data identifies the computer that you are using to view the Site and your approximate geographic location. Again, we do this to track usage patterns.
  * We may use YouTube to host video content. Analytics for this platform may include aggregated and anonymized data on length and location of views, basic demographic details, and engagement rates.

We use Google Analytics or Quantcast, which use Cookies and other similar technologies to collect information about use of the Site anonymously and report website trends. You can learn about Google’s practices by visiting <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/> and you may opt out by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on, available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. The Quantcast privacy policy can be found at <https://www.quantcast.com/privacy/> 

We do not use cookies or other tracking data to send you advertising or promotional material.

Note that most web browsers allow the user to exercise some control of cookies through browser settings. If you delete or block our cookies, some parts of the Site may not work properly, because some of our cookies are necessary for the operation of the Site.

This Online Privacy Policy places all users of the Site on notice about our use of cookies. Your continued use of the Site confirms that you are aware of our use of cookies and have no objection to this.

2.  **Use of Information**

a.  **Personal Information**

Any Personal Information collected through our Site is used for the purpose for which it was provided and other business purposes, including:

  * to periodically alert you to news, events, or information about National Parks Traveler
  * to respond to inquiries,
  * to contact you about surveys, contests or sweepstakes, if any, you entered through our Site and to invite you to participate in new contests or sweepstakes, if any,
  * to customize your web experience or content you receive via email,
  * to encourage social sharing functionality.
  * for internal data analysis, for example to identify trends, enhance current online tools, and plan future digital strategies.

We do not share your Personal Information with any third parties without your consent, except under the following circumstances:

  * to our service providers for the purposes set forth above;
  * with identified entities whose products or services you specifically use or request to receive while you use the Site;
  * in response to legal process and when we believe that doing so is required by law, may be necessary to protect any person’s property, rights, or safety, or to investigate a potential violation of law, will help to enforce any terms of use or other legal agreement, or in the event of a corporate transaction, such as a divestiture, merger, consolidation, bankruptcy or asset transfer or sale; and
  * in accordance with your consent.

b.  **Information Contained in User Content**

Some parts of our Site may allow users to post or transmit messages, comments, screen names, computer files and other materials. If you choose to make personal information public through these options, such information will be considered public and National Parks Traveler will not limit its use or disclosure in the manner described in this Privacy Policy.

3.  **Linked Websites**

Our Site contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. We encourage our users to be aware of when they leave our Site and to read the privacy statements of each website they visit.

4.  **Communications Preferences and Opt-Out**

You can control the type of information collected through our Site, for example, by not accepting cookies from the Site, by erasing all the Site cookies from your browser, or by not providing Personal Information when prompted. To opt out of cookies installed by Google Analytics, please see <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

Your choice will impact your communications preferences, for example we will not be able to respond to inquiries when you do not share your email address with us.

You may opt out of having your personal information used or disclosed for certain purposes. If you wish to update your Personal Information with us or change your communications preferences or if you no longer wish to receive communications from us, please tell us so by email, phone or written letter. Please include your name, your username, and contact details so that we can correctly remove you from our mailing list. Our mailing address is:

nationalparkstraveler.org

P.O. Box 980452

Park City, Utah 84098

United States

We will try to comply with your request(s) as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that we are not required to respond to a customer's request more than once in a calendar year, nor are we required to respond to any request that is not sent through one of the methods designated above.

Even after you cancel your account, copies of some information from your account may remain viewable in some circumstances where, for example, you have shared information with social media or other services. Because of the nature of caching technology, your account may not be instantly inaccessible to others. We may also retain backup information related to your account on our servers for some time after cancellation for fraud detection or to comply with applicable law or our internal security policies. It is not always possible to completely remove or delete all of your information due to technical constraints, contractual, financial or legal requirements.

5.  **Payment Services**

Online transactions are processed through an unaffiliated payment service to enable you to purchase a product or make payments on a third party payment service provider website (“Payment Service”). If you wish to purchase a product or make a payment, you will be directed to a page operated by that Payment Service. Any information that you provide to a Payment Service will be subject to the applicable Payment Service's privacy policy, rather than this Privacy Policy. We have no control over, and are not responsible for, any Payment Service's use of information collected through any Payment Service.

6.  **Information Security**

We take a number of commercially reasonable administrative, technical, personnel and physical steps to safeguard information in our possession from loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure or modification. However, no method of transmitting or storing electronic data is ever completely secure, and therefore we cannot warrant or guarantee that such information will never be accessed, used or released in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.

We will retain your information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or allowed by law.

If you have reason to believe that your use of the Site or engagement with us is no longer secure, please immediately notify us at: [help@nationalparkstraveler.org](mailto:help@nationalparkstraveler.com)

7.  **Children’s Privacy**

Currently, neither our Site, or specific areas or information on our Site, are directed toward children under 13 years of age, nor does our Site knowingly collect information from children under 13. We do not reply to information requests from children under the age of 13, if so identified. A parent or guardian must initiate any requests for information on behalf of children under the age of 13.

8.  **California Residents** _ _

It is our policy not to disclose any Personal Information we collect to third parties for direct marketing purposes. However, California law requires that California residents be given the option to exercise their choice of whether Personal Information may be shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes or not, as well as to receive information specified under relevant California law if Personal Information is disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and you want to inform us whether you permit or refuse the sharing of your personal information with third parties for direct marketing purposes, or if you want to request certain information if your personal information were to be disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes, please contact us as described in the section “Communications Preferences and Opt-Out”.

 **9.  Do Not Track Signals – Including California Law**

We do not track visitors over time and across third party websites to provide targeted advertising. We do not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals from web browsers. Some third party websites may track your browsing activities, enabling them to tailor what they present to you. Please refer to your Web browser or operating system’s website for information on how to modify or control your tracking preferences. 

 As explained in the section of this Privacy Policy concerning “ _Information That May Be Collected Automatically,”_ cookies may be collected for analytic or internal purposes. Most web browsers allow the User to exercise some control of cookies through browser settings. Deleting or blocking our cookies, may keep parts of the Site from working properly, because some of our cookies are necessary for the operation of the Site.

 **10.  Location and Cross-Border Transfers**

By using our Site or providing us with any personal information through the Site, you agree to the transfer, processing and storage of your Personal and Non-Personal Information in countries outside your country of residence, including to or in the United States, which may provide for different data protection rules than in your country.

 **11.  Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the most recent version of the Policy on the Site, along with an indication of the date on which the Policy was amended most recently. We advise you to the Privacy Policy periodically for any updates. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy on the Site. Your continued use of the Site or interaction with the Site after we implement such changes will also constitute your affirmative consent to the revised Privacy Policy.

 **12.  Questions**

If you questions about our privacy policy or practices of the Site, please contact us at:
